# Thomas C. Hsu

Mobile: (732) 647-5373 | Email: <a href="mailto:thomaschsu@gmail.com">thomaschsu@gmail.com</a> | Holmdel, NJ 07733 | Linkedln: <a href="mailto:https://www.linkedin.com/in/tomchsu/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/tomchsu/</a> | Portfolio: <a href="https://thomaschsu.github.io/">https://thomaschsu.github.io/</a>

**GitHub:** https://github.com/thomaschsu

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Full Stack Developer with a focus on the front-end. Experienced Front-end Developer with a proven background in developing user-friendly websites and web applications. Well-versed in various programming languages including JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Node, and more. A proactive professional who enjoys systematically testing websites for bugs and debugging errors. Expertly equipped to apply knowledge and expertise in web development to a like-minded company to ensure quality user interaction that produces optimal results.

#### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Responsive Web Design, JSON, React
- Magento 1 & 2 E-commerce
- WordPress
- Node.js, Firebase
- Express
- SEO
- MongoDB

- GIT, GitHub
- Bootstrap, Materialize
- APIs, AJAX
- CLI
- Microsoft Office Suite and Adobe Suite
- MySQL
- Heroku

#### **APPLICATIONS BUILT**

### MRA International Company Website – Front-End Developer

- Company website that provided the world with information about MRA International
- WordPress, HTML, CSS, Graphics Design
- Live: https://mrainternational.com/start/

### MRA International Storefront – Front-End Developer / Catalog Manager

- Storefront for MRA International that sold computers and electronics
- Created multiple stores for different Universities that sold configured HP desktops, laptops, and equipment
- Magento 1 & 2, HTML, CSS, Graphics Design
- **Live:** https://store.mrainternational.com/

### My Movie List - Lead Front-End Developer

- Designed website layout and theme
- Full Stack website for keeping track of all the movies that you have watched in your lifetime, along with a score
- React, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Animate.css, BootStrap, Materialize, BootStrap, Graphics Design
- **GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/thomaschsu/mymovielist">https://github.com/thomaschsu/mymovielist</a> | **Live:** <a href="https://mmlist.herokuapp.com/">https://mmlist.herokuapp.com/</a>

### Bluewave Fitness – Lead Front-End Developer

- A fitness website that stores your workouts, uses a login, calculates your BMI all in one place
- Ability to save workouts, clean UI, and a chat function

Thomas C. Hsu Page 2

- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs, ¡Query, Materialize, Graphics Design
- **GitHub:** <a href="https://github.com/thomaschsu/bluewavefitness">https://github.com/thomaschsu/bluewavefitness</a> | **Live:** <a href="https://agile-beyond-80440.herokuapp.com/">https://agile-beyond-80440.herokuapp.com/</a>

### Goodmovies - Lead Front-End Developer

- Website dedicated to finding movies based on Rotten Tomatoes ratings
- Ability to save favorite movies into Firebase
- HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Firebase, APIs, BootStrap, jQuery
- GitHub: <a href="https://github.com/thomaschsu/good-movies/">https://github.com/thomaschsu/good-movies/</a> | Live: <a href="https://thomaschsu.github.io/good-movies/">https://thomaschsu.github.io/good-movies/</a>

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

MRA International - Long Branch, NJ

March 2013 – February 2018

## Website Administrator, Web Developer, IT Technician, Inside Sales Representative

- Took a lead role in the production and maintenance of a front-end Magento and WordPress company website to increase sales and marketing efforts.
- Built and managed graphics to boost the overall look and feel of the company websites to enhance user experience.
- Took part in a massive company project that required imaging thousands of laptops and desktops for the Elizabeth school districts in a timely and proficient manner.
- Provided client services for malfunctioning desktops and laptops and networked with customers in addition to being an inside sales representative.

**DuPont** – Parlin, NJ June 2007 – August 2007 | May 2008 – August 2008 | June 2011 – July 2011 *Manufacturing Technician LSE* 

- Provided inter-departmental services in multiple team environments that assisted with the processing, inspection, and packaging of Cyrel Flexographic plates to maintain a near uptime of 90% increasing production.
- Collaborated with distribution to get products to where they needed to be in an efficient and structured way.
- Gained knowledge in patience, hard work, and how to be a team player.

### **EDUCATION**

Rutgers University – New Brunswick, NJ

April 2018 – October 2018

Full Stack Web Development – Coding Program

Rutgers University - New Brunswick, NJ

September 2007 – January 2012

School of Arts and Sciences | School of Information Technology and Informatics | Bachelor of Arts

Major: Information Technology and Informatics

Minor: Psychology

Received Dean's List (Fall 2011)